Watch in our last class we are discussing
Regarding business organization and not
I was telling you guys this last
In class on how business organization works
Business organization is created from
Before forming any business organization
Like, in today's date, the government also
I want to do business in India
The organization has to be developed so that India
More employment is being created in
Not like I told you guys.
If India has to develop then at least
One in 10 people should start a business.
So this is the business environment.
The commercial knowledge paper that you people have to take
Foundation is taught from school level
Even in level you can do intermediate and final
Reach the level of Executive Final
Even in the level, you will not find this
A special extension part of the subject
If you have to study then there will be more practicality in it.
You should try to understand that this
in Business Environment or Commercial Knowledge
The main theme is what the government mainly wants.
that are inside chartered inside CS
Inside CMA or any commerce
Regarding business within the professional
Increase awareness and understanding
There is consciousness, isn't it, because if chartered
Cannes will be CS Cannes will be CMA Cannes will be
So may these people also help in nation building
Maybe you understand the point, right?
Developing business is nation building
Nation building is what we have to do, right?
We have to build it somewhere and
Like you can see one thing all day long.
Maybe this recent West Bengal is again
Voting is coming in, like in West Bengal.
If assembly elections are coming up then
In the assembly elections, it will depend on
Will the power change or not, what does it mean?
Whether Mamata Didi's government will remain or not, then this
The existence or non-existence of the government is the most important issue.
The important thing depends on
Mamta Didi's government job could be created
Are you unable to understand the matter?
How much employment are you
If you are able to create then this employment
Where will job creation take place?
Where did the answer to all these questions come from?
It can only be done with one solution
That is the development of business
Organization I told you West Bengal
If you told me about the government
Bihar Government UP in Similar Way
Government of Assam Government of Manipur
Government of Maharashtra Government of Rajasthan
Government, any government, if you look at
The same issue occurs most often
Creation is useless, so much useless, keep growing
Am I saying the right thing
hmm hello this is it so t i the main issue is this
We will keep the rest of the issue aside.
They only provide infrastructure, right?
Is development happening or not?
Is the road being built or not? It's okay.
Or is there any study going on in school?
It is happening that there are doctors in hospitals
No, this kind of problem is there.
But even more important is that we
We only see which one
Most people during the time of government
If you have got a job then job me
Whether you will get it or not, the biggest reason behind this is
What is the most important fact behind this?
Important fact to business organization
Yes, it is there, isn't it? So today I am with you all.
Some Special Matter of Business Organization
to develop a business organization
of that business organization at the time of
What should be the portfolio and some
There will be a special discussion in the banking sector.
So that you people can get into business level
At least an idea in the banking sector
How to get and banking business
It was made in the 90s, okay, so today
There is no banking business in the debt of any other
Banking business is also a place to become a business
If it can be made then I will discuss it with you.
I am going to do HDFC Bank and
ICICI Bank and State Bank of India
to discuss studies within but
More important than that is business
What are the portfolios in the organization?
That's the kind of matter I ask you
I will discuss what will happen in this.
Your business environment is that of commerce
This knowledge will be announced in the exam also.
Very helpful to you
will be
Okay, let me first teach you a little about math.
I will tell you
Screen shared
no yes
Sir, first of all, must have seen this.
I told you in the last class that I was just
Recalling you once
I am looking for development in any business.
For in fear to meet no one
Environment Competitive Environment
Always means always environment compatible
lives vi matlab environment compt in the
Sense what to do in a business scenario
What should not be made in the market
If someone wants to come, he always feels
that there are other companies like mine, so my
How will the business run? Kind of thinking.
Competitive Environment in 1970
It used to run in 1990 and it still runs in 2020
Same thing will work in 201 as well and same thing will work in 201
It will remain, just the method will change a little bit.
Do you guys believe this one thing or not?
Would you ever ask your parents that
Just ask them that when their people study
Was there competition or not when those people used to do it?
It is said that nowadays we use such words
Nowadays there is a lot of competition so one of my
The question running in my mind is whether the competition first
No
What did you guys think
today
There was always competition
What was the population of India in 1947?
anyone has an idea
Does anyone have any idea that in 1947
What is the population of India
It was approximately Rs 30 crore.
The population of India in 1947 was
Approx 30 to 40
There was no proper census at that time.
Because we were going crazy fighting.
People even died, still let's go for 30 crores.
The population at that time was approximately 30 crore.
But it was in 47, then by the end of 1970 it would have reached 80.
What will be the population in the future? It is too much.
There was a little more growth stage in India
It had already arrived but still 60-70
Just imagine at the time of 70 crores
There would be competition even for 60-70 crores.
At our level, the population is currently 130 crores.
There is a competition in this even today.
The population will grow further
If population growth increases then the competition level will increase.
It will also increase accordingly, like before.
I am telling you a very simple logic.
It is not that there was less competition earlier.
I don't think there is much competition at all.
ok but there's one thing I feel like
If the population is at a low level earlier,
I was okay, the population was low before.
Earlier there was less organization.
Was
Hello, is that correct or not?
Yes sir, yes sir, yes sir, population less organ
also less current population
High current population is increasing at a high rate
If it is there then an organization is also being formed
If so, somewhere the economy is finding itself
Does it balance itself?
It does not balance the economy at all.
It's a misconception, I'll tell you again and again.
The economy will balance out like a balance sheet
Does the balance work or not?
Hello, does the balance sheet balance or not?
does
Yes sir, the balance sheet can be postponed.
No matter how much capital you invest, no matter how much you
Take Asset Asset
Take this Joe
The game of liability plus capital and asset
No matter how much capital you invest in it
No matter how much asset you have on your business,
Purchase it, take as much credit as you want here.
No matter how much current and fixed assets you purchase
He balances it out somewhere.
Does it or not if you have asset suppose
You brought cash to your business, okay?
Cash on business brought extra Rs crore
So your capital also increases.
Crore's yes or no if you start your own business
Fixed Asset Purchase from Fixed Asset Capital of
Do you do that or purchase a land?
If it is worth crores then it would be a fixed asset worth crores.
that does not happen
Hello, are you able to understand the matter of 2 crores?
Fixed asset as if mortgaged to someone
If you take a loan of Rs. 2 crores then here
If there is credit in the market because your
He has fixed assets worth Rs 2 crore.
By taking mortgage in the market
You took a loan or credit of Rs 2 crore.
Take
If you take it, you will have this balance somewhere.
Please tell me this will not happen
He runs every year's data by being forward.
He never matches, this is what we do
People Accounting Principles in Concepts
You learn, don't you, just listen to what I say
Simple means the way accounting
The system tallies the balance sheet in the
Similar fashion in the similar fashion Ye Jo
What I am telling you about business is that when
The system was worth Rs 60-70 crore even at that time.
Organization used to balance job level
If it was less then there was competition at that time also.
There used to be balance, now the population rate is high
There is too much organization
Comparatively quite organization also high
There is a lot of organization going on at this rate.
If a lot of business is being created then the economy is going somewhere
No one can balance anyone's situation.
Doesn't it stop for a bit, wait wait wait
There's a lot of population growth later.
If an organization is formed, you should balance it like this
So it doesn't happen, it will be automatic, okay?
When the time demands it, it becomes automatic.
Yes, it is true but still
130 crores in a country like India
There is pressure, okay, so much population pressure
There is only one way to handle that
is developing a business organization
And to develop this business organization
You need to do some research for this.
Mainly what research should you do
You should do a budget analysis.
You should do financial analysis.
You should do management analysis.
Market research analysis should be done
I told you in the last class.
I recalled that business organizations
What matters to you before developing?
You should pay attention to her company when you
If you make it, what do you know about the company?
Knowledge on the matter should be enhanced
Look, look, here it is said very lovingly.
Students are expected to have knowledge
of Development in the Corporate World by
Reading Financial Papers and Visiting
Websites of corporates on a regular basis
Now stick to the regular market Sir Aap Money
Follow the control, you follow the live maintenance
Okay, if you are a magazine, then follow it.
There are lots of things you can do Company Website
Follow your company from somewhere.
Get the data, I have one for you guys.
I am building up a blog, you can see there
People get everything on a regular basis.
I will go so that you people don't have to wander around
Read it, okay, I work for him regularly.
I am staying here so that I can get the updates in the regular market.
I will send it to you so that you
People stay at the forefront of commerce okay
What a Company Overview Will Usually Include
What should a company overview include?
It is important to know who is corporate and what
It does which company what does that
What is the vision and mission of the company?
What is the history and who is on the management team?
Portfolio of business products and services
What's Who in the Compute Scenario
How is the financial performance doing?
What is the current position of the business in the market?
Is it in the news or not? What is the growth plan?
running into someone doing margin
that he is not acquiring anyone
Didn't you do it, maybe you took it to some other company?
that it was not taken, that means acquisition
Do you understand or not what action means?
It is when one company buys another company
Okay, that's called an acquisition joint.
Venture is doing a joint venture with someone
What does it mean to do business together?
Such a concept will increase likes
Keeping this point of view in mind
I have presented the case study of two companies for you people.
Three company's to discuss with
I thought one of which is HDFC Bank.
ICICI Bank is ok ADFC Bank is
I will discuss the most current matter with you.
I will find out who he is, when he came, why he came, okay?
Is
Everything After This Discussing It
You will also get knowledge of business organization.
How will a bank develop and from where?
You will get an idea of ​​how far it has reached.
No one becomes a sir overnight, this is it
ICICI Bank is fine and one is State
Bank of India is aware of these three things.
I'm going to discuss it with you, okay.
So let me tell you one by one.
First of all, I would like to share with you about HDFC Bank.
talk about
I will do it sir, you guys understand
what I am going to discuss
Hello, I understand you guys.
Yes sir, look at your banking business.
You will also get an idea, yes, say something.
want to speak
Okay, so you also have an idea for banking business.
You will get business along with it
development of the organization which
Its entire process is practical.
You will get an idea so that you can start a project.
You have to do business in your exam
You can ask them anything about the organization.
Can you answer the question related to this?
Because you are learning the matter practically
Okay, so as you can see here.
Business Organization P Current Joe I
I am going to discuss ADFC Bank
I will compare later, first a little
I will tell you the matter one by one first.
I will tell you and then compare it later, okay?
Previously in Each and Every Point of View
Discuss what the comparison process will be like.
The process is something like
will be
Discuss Individually
Regarding
HDFC Bank and HDFC
Group ICICI Bank & ICICI
Group and State Bank of India Sir Bank
At the time of opening the account, we
Have you heard about the three banks or not?
listen to most
We hear more about these three banks.
I wrote my name, did you guys know?
It seems that this is the most popular in India currently.
One of the top banks that comes to our mind is
There would have been a build up from childhood
Yes, and yes sir sir sir, so this is a kind of
It comes to mind that HDFC Bank is very
ICICI Bank is very good
State Bank of India is also very good.
what is this game of good and bad why good
why is it bad okay is it really
Is it really good or is it really bad?
How is the situation inside the bank?
Recently you all know that there is a bank
Jo's Bank, its performance level is very
It's gotten worse than I told you to someone
If you discussed this in class then this
private this is a private player okay this
ADFC Bank is a private player.
Look sir, it is listed on the stock exchange.
Meaning publicly listed shares are available to the public
It is a public listed company but its
The operation that is handled is private.
ADC handles the level
Stock exchange listed means public
Listed is publicly listed but controlled
By Private Organization Public Listed
But controlled by private organization
Same to Same for the ICICI But State
This bank is publicly listed and
Control by Government, okay Government
It is owned and public as well, so if I
If I were to compare in real terms, HDFC
The comparison with ICI is quite appropriate.
But I also took SBI along with me because
So that I can also tell you that private
The competition that exists at the level is there but
If a private bank is linked to a government bank
What if I go and compare a little?
Maybe okay and recently banking
Some upgrades are also coming in the sector
I will discuss that with you then
Let me take the matter further, so first of all
First you see the story of HDFC Bank today
Today's story will be about banks.
I thought I'd talk to you about it
As you can see Eddie Banks
Ltd. E Indian Banking and Financial
Service company headquartered in Mumbai
Maharashtra it is base of
1014 Permanent Employee means you think
Can you tell how many employees it has, one lakh?
There are more than one employee in ADFC Bank
LA 414 is okay so many people work on it
Let's do this, this is the data of June 30, 2019
ADFC Bank is India's Largest
Remember Private Sector Banks by Assets
Sir the rls r knowledge is ok private
Sector banks have the highest asset holdings.
If anyone has it, it is with HDFC.
It is the largest bank in India by
market
The capital in the capital market is Sir Capital
Do you guys understand what it means or not?
I understood you just a while ago
was explaining the balance sheet and in the balance sheet
I was showing you the capital, so the balance sheet
Why do we show capital in [?] because the company
does business with that much capital in the market
Hey dear
Yes sir, yes sir, ok, the meaning of market capital
What is that the banks which are in the market
How much money is he doing business with?
The more money one is making in business
He can expand his business as much as possible.
But it doesn't happen overnight, for
It takes time to grow a business
It is not that someone is born absolutely
Brings business money just like that
Not starting with obviously little capital
It should happen but with the proper flowing of
The Business Time and Money in Business
Growing as you see the market here
This is according to Capital S of March 2020
India's current top private bank
Sector is doing well and market capital is also good.
topping
Okay, what else am I going to tell you?
I'll look at a little history
Yes, this HDFC Bank has come.
It was a subsidiary of the earlier HDFC
The bank did not come, please pay attention first
The Housing Development Finance Corporation
ok hdfc was only hdfc housing
Fina is its full form, this is it, please remember
Rakhna Housing Development Finance
Corporation was its name, then ADC
The bank was incorporated in 1994 then ADC
The bank was created in 1994, meaning it was
You used to finance only to build a house
Do you understand the point of developing housing?
Whether for housing at government level
or private level housing
To develop the housing level, this
Basically I used to do finance work then
HDFC Bank was incorporated when
The government saw that Bhai A Housing Finance
If this company HDFC is doing well then
Why not give it a banking license?
Okay, so they went and got a bank license.
I will also tell you some recent stories.
That recently there are some such institutions
Which works on a good payment system
He is saying that he got the banking license.
It's okay and I got it very recently.
And some people have payment bank.
I got a license if I give you a little
If I give you an idea, then say something here.
I can I
You will get recent bank updates.
Recent Bank
Licensed banks and payment banks both slightly
would have been different
Payment banks have all kinds of facilities.
It doesn't happen but yes there is some facility like a bank.
It definitely means it would have been under RBI control.
Is there any recent bank among you guys?
I'm waiting for your answer
That recently some banks have come which are complete
If the bank has come then tell me the name of some such bank.
You can do something that is very recent, which
I got the license just by saying a couple of names.
will be
green nuts very old bank
juicy
DBS Foreign Bank is a very old bank.
Singapore
Of
PNB is a very old bank in India.
some other name of
Tell me, thank you, thank you, or good by too old
No Baba Fa Ha Mathur Finance Mathur
Finance is not a bank, Mathur Finance
NBFC Muthoot Finance please remember
Here Priyanshu is saying wrong, this is a mistake
don't do it
If it is not there then it is called NBFC what is it called
NBFC means non-banking
If you are a commerce student and want to do all this
If you make a mistake, I mean Sir, I will definitely accept you.
Respect will all disappear because you people
I explain this very often to non-banking
Finance
A company or bank performs the same functions as a bank.
That is loan provided without deposit
Sir, he does not keep it as mortgage but this
Your non-banking finance company is in this
You cannot make a deposit and you cannot keep it as a mortgage.
Can you sir Bandhan Bank yes Bandhan Bank recent
I wrote my name in the bank Bandhan Bank Recent
Its come in the bank in 2015, okay 2015
This bank came into existence in 2000, its owner is
He is a Bengali, meaning after a long time someone Bengali
Meaning it is very big in the business sector
Becoming the Owner of the Organization Seriously
Proud to be a Bengali in that case means when
Chandrashekhar Ghosh was born, okay Chandrashekhar
Ghosh means after a long time because normally
South Indian Side to Western Indian Side
Many people have built up business from this
ok like adac bank iii bank all
There has been some build-up at a private level.
Mahindra but Bandhan Bank in Bengali level
If it has been built up then it is something to be proud of.
And to tell you the truth, the current performance level too
Its running very well Recent Bank
I also came across another bank, IDFC First Bank.
I have a student who got a job.
You must have heard their name IDFC First.
Banker ID IDFC First Bank in
I have a student who is getting a job after doing an enrolment.
After doing Mila Enam he got a job here.
It is quite new, look, in 2015 or even in 2015
It has come, right, Bandhan also came in 2015.
Basically what I want to say is that recently
Some banks have also come and payment banks
There are many sir like Airtel payment
You must have heard the name of the bank Paytm Payment Bank
Airtel Payment Bank Paytm Payment Bank
PhonePe Payment Bank is fine.
This type of payment bank is mainly for payment purposes.
As you can see, according to
G Pay also has a license for G Pay.
Passed license too
Whatever is there on G, it also does it.
So in this way all this can be done only after taking RBI license.
If I work then mainly this is what I mean to say
Let's say that right now that is not the matter, this is the matter.
I was talking in AC so this happened
Where was its registered office in Mumbai?
It is the first corporate in Maharashtra.
Office and Full Service Branch at Sos House
Orli is a place in Bombay Sir Bandra Orli
Okay, there's also a ceiling, you see the bridge.
What is happening with so much network?
Is there any problem that 's' is coming out again and again?
remained
Is s of June 309 The Banks Distribution
Network was at 5500 branches 5500 branches
Its population is in 64 cities as of 2019.
2764 cities can you imagine the bank also
installed
430000 Point of Selling Terminals POS
Terminals means from where those small
Business also means level in the village side
Can develop and issued 23 lakh sorry
2 crore
35700 2 crore 35700 debit cards know this
It shows what the company's business is and
12 million credit card financial
12 million credit cards were issued in 2017.
They issued a debit card worth Rs 35700.
You can understand that this will help you in your business.
You will get an idea about what business to do currently.
ADFC Bank is doing it okay so once
Let me give you an overview of what an ADC is.
What is the type of bank? It is public.
What you should not understand by meaning
Whether a company is public or private
How will you know if he is in the stock market?
Even though it is listed as private, it is public.
It will be said in the stock market
Even if you are private just by being listed
Then you will be made public because you
If you take even a single penny from the public then
what do I even tell you
I will accept it if you take even one rupee from the public.
Even if you take the money, what agreement will I give you?
I will give it, I will tell the public, see this in NAC
It is listed on the National Stock Exchange
It was listed on the National Stock Exchange under this name in
NSC is listed in India in BSC
It is also listed on the Bombay Stock Exchange.
It is also listed, it is ok, the code is ok
In BSC, in Sensex, in NSC
It is in the top 50 in Nifty, meaning it is in the top 50.
It means it is a very good organization.
That's why there are a lot of companies inside this NSC.
We work but the top 50 people who come in it
Yes, we are the ones who watch movies, sir.
What should we tell you about this
Whenever people watch the news of the stock market,
There is news on TV that Nifty
Sensex Nifty is falling and rising
Whether you see it or not, look at today's
The market scenario is that today the market is a little
It looks down, it was a little up and then down.
Then it's going on a little bit in red vision.
Hello to you, which Nifty 50 is visible
Yes sir, this Nifty 50 means this Nifty.
50 means that there is a lot of volatility in the market.
All the companies are listed but all of them
The company is on the National Stock Exchange.
It maintains the best of Nifty for everyone
You don't get a chance in 50, okay, which is very
Businesses that do well have a strong market share
The holding is also very good, the weightage is very high
Well, how does this all happen?
For this you need to know the stock market.
If you have to study then go and learn all this.
You will go, but I will surely torment you just this much
Business students you have to know this nifty
At least do you know enough to know that if the market
In four to three thousand companies inside Nifty
It is listed in BC NC so from that
Those who get a chance in the top 50 and they
Company
This index of ours is in their index.
Trading takes place in the market, meaning people
If you want, invest money directly in Nifty
You can, okay, directly in Nifty like
The current price of one unit of Nifty is something like this
It is running 11:48 so you can directly access it.
You can invest your money if maximum
If companies go to you, your money will also increase.
And if Maximum Company goes down then your
If the penny falls, whatever happens
It will not be possible to do it slowly
Slowly, what kind of work does this
This type of work is called financial service
The company was founded in 1994 in Nice
Who was the founder of Hummus Bhai Park, remember Hummus
Bhai Paar Paare Marathi title is Sir Hummus Bhai
Parekh had made it to HDFC Bank.
Head Quarter Mumbai Maharashtra Area
Shyamala Gopinath, People's Current Affairs of India
Non-Executive Chairperson and Sashidhar
Jagdish, Chief Executive Officer, Yad
Remember the questions in the exam.
Shashidhar Jagdish asks in MCQ, is it okay?
Who are these people of ADAC Bank?
Your MCQ question is Tswai
I am saying this, am I not just saying it?
What product does ADFC Bank have in its main portfolio?
The business area is as you can see.
it has a credit card okay its
Credit card is consumer banking
We all do business, banking is different.
So its main business is finance.
Giving loans to people and also insurance
HDFC Insurance is your business.
Have you heard the name HDFC Investments?
Banking means through them one of their
Mutual funds are also available through this.
Investment banking means
Investment banking means any big company
If you want to raise money from the market
It is also called merchant banker.
If a big company is the first to enter the market
Earn money from the market when the time comes
Want to take IPO in the stock market
If you want to get listed for the first time
It is called merchant banking or
Underwriters when you guys get a little older
If you go to the intermediate level,
There you will have to learn an account.
Underwriting of shares, then at that time you
You will learn how his accounts are maintained.
Right now you should know that any company which
Want to raise money from the market for the first time
If yes, then it is good at that time.
Mortgage business is just mortgage loans.
Private banking is private
Equity Wealth Management Meaning Wealth
Management means basically mutual funds are okay
This is a mutual fund from Wealth Management
means HDFC Mutual
You can also invest money in the market through funds.
If you can plant it then there are lots of area
Its product portfolio on top of this
Whose build did they make?
I am telling you the portfolio of HDFC.
I am telling you about my portfolio, it is good ADAC
Who built the bank and who inaugurated it?
At whose time did it happen? At that time, the country
Look who used to be the Finance Minister.
Sir Manmohan Singh Respected Manmohan Singh
Their financial knowledge is truly impressive.
It falls on their time in India
There has been a lot of development at the financial level
Manmohan Singh is a very good finance man.
Sir was a scholar, I probably forget only one thing.
His becoming the Prime Minister and everything else
He is a very nice person, age of 30.
June 2019 The Bank Distribution Network
I have already told you how good its revenue is.
Look at the model, its revenue in 2020
Comparing $2 billion to $21 billion
Because after this we have to do your
ICICI's No. 147, keep it all in writing
memorize the data so that you
We have to go ahead, the current data is running smoothly.
The current is fixed at one
Lakh
68 68 crores earning so much revenue
Hey, I mean you understand this in 2020
Revenue means sales by selling it.
Revenue has come, how much income has been earned
how much did
1132 crores means operating of 16 billion
Income is its net income
7253 crores net worth 3.8 billion in 2020
Income means after paying other expenses etc.
Look how much assets he has, 220
billion
Rs crore sorry 15 crore 58 lakh crore
5883 crore
It has total assets worth Rs 5830.
How much equity is there, that means how many people
Total equity shareholder money
It has deposited Rs 17,5810 crore with it.
Total equity is valued at 25
Billion US Dollars, okay, ADFC Bank
What is HDFC's ownership stake in
Meaning my ownership is at 26, the rest of the people
They have invested in the market
It is in ownership, do you understand?
26.1 It has ownership of this much employees
I work here and want to know the details.
So visit their website and get the details
address of
Try it sir, are you guys understanding anything, enjoy it.
Want to know about HDFC Bank
I am Yes Sir ADFC Bank
m ADFC Bank merge with Times Bank in
February 2000 This was the first merger of two
Private Banks in New Generation Private
Sector Category Time Banks Wa Able In
Bennett Coleman & Co. Ltd. These basically
Times of India ka paper hota hai naam
have you heard
You must have heard the name of Times of India paper.
You must be reading this from Times of India.
The company is Times of India, the company whose
That's the paper, the name of the company is Bennett.
Koman & Co. Ltd. Okay, that's the group.
The Times of India is run in India
Commonly known as The Times Group is commonly
Times Group is known by this name.
India's largest media conglomerate
Meaning it has a huge influence in the media.
Sir, Times of India Group's Times
Now Times Channel Lots of Times of
India's paper is okay, Times Magazine
Okay, so these times do a lot of things.
Stock market investment is also a form of investment.
If there is some related p also then times like this
So, they have established their dominance.
The first march was held in 2000, which was very
In a big private level, March was the first
Marcher of two private banks in 2008
Centurion Bank WA Ad by ADAC Bank
Centurion Bank was the first bank in India.
ADAC Bank Board Approved Performance of
Centurion Bank for 95.1 billion in one of
The Margin of Fossil Sector in India is ok
So you can see what ADFC has done.
feat
It's okay, there is investment etc.
Its listing and shareholding is
Look at the current ADFC Bank total
Look at his shareholding pattern, you can find information on equity.
Shares of ADFC Bank listed on Kisum
Bombay Stock Exchange National Stock Exchange
OK Eaton American Deposit Share Its
American Depositary Shares also means
People in America also have access to ADAC Bank.
New York Stocks You Can Invest In
Listed on the exchange, please point to
B means note because you should also know this
Where should the business have its global presence?
This business is going to ADFC Bank
Business is so developed globally, so developed
that these are its depository shares American
He also sells it on the stock exchange and that someone
Foreigners who through the American Stock Exchange
in the US through your Demat account
If you want to purchase then those Indian shares
The company is in India, but this
The company is also listed on the New York Stock Exchange.
is listed and even there if people
Looks like there's good money to be made in this company.
It means the company has good growth, so that
You can also invest money from there through ADR
American Depositary Shares, all of this.
You will know the entire matter in detail by reading the share market.
You will understand, but for now, I will tell you the basics.
What I have told you is enough and the global
Depository Reserve is called GDR.
Global Depository Receipts are listed on
The Luxembourg Stock Exchange over to GDR
Represents one equity share of
GDRs of one share of ADC Bank
It means that there is some global level from there also.
But ADAC can purchase shares of the bank
So the current share holding pattern if you
You see, this promoter has data till 2015.
It is from the group which has been created by people i.e. Hasmukh
Red
Park Hasmukh Lal did not say the right thing.
No, not exactly cheerful brother, sorry cheerful brother Parikh
When he created it, the share holding
Promoter group shares at 26 in the pattern
Holding is meaning the people who created this
What does Foreign Institutional Investors mean?
Foreign Companies Foreign Institution Meaning
Foreign Mutual Fund Companies Foreign
Insurance companies are any foreign in this
Europe Russia Germany America Individual countries
Why do people invest in China?
also there okay so this like HDFC
China also has a good holding in it.
Think 20.4% on Foreign Institutional
Individual shareholders mean us like you
People who invest in the stock market
Let's see their percentage holding.
can you 8.5 okay bodies corporate
Meaning the second company in ADAC Bank
I have invested and kept it at 75
Insurance companies like LIC General
Insurance Private Insurance Companies
Ok
5.38 Unit Trust of India
Government mutual fund is a sector
Wealth management is a part of this.
Unit Trust of India Mutual Funds
There are also these, one from this, one from this
Axis Bank also took part share holding
A Uni Trust of India was created
Axis Bank was created by selling percentages
Okay, I'm giving you the information.
NRI OCB shareholding is at 8.65
Meaning Non-Returning Non-Resident Indians
and overseas citizens of Indians in these
The total financials are at 29.
Institution and banks means other banks
Or any financial institution like
Was some Muthoot Finance type telling me that?
can be anyone who is a financial non-profit
Banking hai woh 2.75 & ADR GDR means
You see, I just told you about ADR and GDR
explained okay ADR GDR what you guys
The normal concept of ADR/GDR
Clear is American Depository Ripple End
What is Global Depository Ripple?
Normally, are you able to understand this point?
hai hello yes sir ok ya american depository
Shares and Global Deposit Re through
18.7 is the total share, thus 100%
The holding pattern is that of HDFC
bank's current system
I understand it is not that
The entire share is his and he is publicly available.
This is the convenience that whenever any company
If it comes publicly then it is like this
The company grows with investment and
Their capital increases in business
Growth comes and the whole game continues.
Yes sir, okay, so you can understand how
A company was formed in 94 and gradually
Slowly becoming India's largest bank
Transfer is done, okay, some controversies
You can also see the controversy, okay?
The Reserve Bank of India has occasionally
told me about diligence okay
Right now, I want to discuss all this with you.
It is not necessary, but you can see this data.
Yes, it was made the best bank in 2019.
Tha New Private Sector Best Bank
Award Winner in Innovations of 11
Inclusive Finance Indian Awards 2019
I was made in I have received many awards and ranked
First in 2019 Branch Top 75 Most
Valuable Indian Brand HDFC Bank Vaz
The Feature for the Sixth Kankut Years Sixth Year
Till now he has been consistently ranked among the most
Honoured Company List Institutional
Found inside All Asia for Investors
It was okay, except Japan, India is the best.
Bank Euro Money Award Excellence in 2019
Received Bank of the Year Best Large Bank
Business Today Award
was the best large bank and fastest
Growing Bank Best Large Bank and
Fastest Growing Bank in the World
Found in the business world
Is this a large bank or a small bank?
No Best Bank in India 2016
ADFC received many awards.
You can see how it is
You have built your business well
Clearing the overview of AC Bank
Sir, this is what I told you from my note.
Here I will tell you about the institute's mat
If I show you from there, you will see it from there as well.
I have suddenly told you something more
You must have told me, see the details on this.
Hey Bank, you see all this.
There is not much detail, I have not given you anything.
Specially told me a lot or some special points
You can take a look at some of its markets.
Some brands run on Paytm Payments
Small Micro Investment by P Hasi Bank
Bank is watch banking 30 minute auto loan
A program has been created for Minute to Healer Loan
A program has been made for two wheels in 15 minutes
You will get a loan of Rs. 30 lakhs i.e. bike loan.
Auto loan will be available in minutes, some such concept
Has brought e-payment gateways made digital
The wallet system is built like this.
ADAC Bank is gradually expanding its product
The rest is developing the portfolio further
I have already told you the philosophy of this thing.
What is it, take a look
Lena Aditya Puri is its current Managing Director.
director is managing director okay
I told you about recent changes in Chairman.
Told you it's okay and is the Chief Financial Officer
Srinivasan Vaidyanath ok chief
Financial Officer
what is its philosophy to be a world
Class Indian Bank's philosophy is that it
Green India's World Class Indian Bank
This is what ADFC Bank wants to become.
It's a big challenge and that's what he proved.
already okay how private level
Where can I, a guy, get this from?
Come on sir, let's talk a lot about HDFC Bank.
Take a look at ICICI Bank
Sir, this too has its headquarter in Mumbai.
Multinational banking means it also
International branches are very financial
Service Company with Registered Office in Vadodara
Its registered office is in Dara, Gujarat.
I have corporate office in Mumbai ok
Meaning it had registered the business
The ICICI company was registered in Gujarat.
I later moved to Mumbai to do my
Corporate Office Made It Offers Wide Range
of Banking Products and Financial
Service for Corporate Retail Customers through
Variety of Delivery The Bank has a Network
5 to 75 branches spread across India
I have 5275 branches and
1559 means 89 ATMs across India and
It has its presence in 17 countries.
meaning in the world which probably also means ADAC
It is not available in 17 countries of the world.
II Bank is one of the big four
Bank of India The Bank has subsidiary
In the UK it has a subsidiary in the UK
It has a subsidiary in Canada and
Branches in United States Singapore
Bahrain Hong Kong Qatar Oman Abu Dhabi South
Africa Bangladesh Malaysia
Indonesia is such a vast area
It is a subsidiary, can you understand how much
This is a big bank, this is also a very big bank.
But in the end, you have to compare
You will find out whether HDFC is bigger or ICICI.
I know who is bigger than him.
You will get real data here, don't you?
This is also listed on the stock market, it is 5th
Made in January 1994, Sir 5th January
1994 Registered Office I told you
People Girish of Area SARD World Wide
Chandra Chaturvedi Sandeep Bakshi MDN
Its CEO is also the same product like
That is the revenue model of ADFC, you
You can see Rs 149000
Its current revenue model is Rs 786 crore.
2020 revenue is operating income 78 to
Net income is Rs 68.2 crore, this much has been given
Sir 956 assets worth Rs 6.31 crore are also less.
There is no 1 crore
377 sorry 1 1 crore 37 7292 crore worth of assets
Its equity is also doing very well.
And you see growth in everything.
Seeing green means growth in everything
Running Keep It Up 18
a million sorry
Its total equity is Rs 8.45 crore.
Apple is less than HDC sir 84000 ME
Its a me of one lakh something in HDFC
Sir, did you see its app level?
ICCI is a little less
Take a look at the full form of ICICI
Like I told you the full form of HDFC.
Told that Housing Development Finance
Corporation is also similar to ICICI Bank.
What is the full form of this, it was created
The bank was not formed earlier, it was formed earlier
Industrial Credit and Investment
Corporation of India please point to be
Note this is also an important general knowledge.
Financial GK of Industrial Credit
and Investment Corporation created it
To provide loans at the industrial level
If someone had to create an industry
Someone has to make an investment
In business, ICICI has to do that.
The firm was established in India after 94
It was transferred to the bank in
But first he would work at this level first.
Industrial credit at the lower level
Investment Corporation of India and
Indian Financial Institution Holy N
Sabari 1994 in Badora Parent
Company Was Firm In
95 55 It was built a long time ago in 1955
was formed in S.A. as a joint venture of the
Sir, are you able to understand the World Bank joint venture?
of India through a joint venture with the World Bank
It was built by the Government of India.
India's Public Sector Banks and Public
Sector Insurance Companies to Provide
Project Financing to Indian Industry
The Bank was built for this purpose.
was founded as the Industrial Credit
and Investment Corporation the parent
The company was later in March with the bank.
In this, the parent company was ICICI.
Marched it along the bank
ICICI Bank Latch Internet Banking
Operation In
1998 Let me tell you that in India today
Does internet banking work on this date?
Internet Banking in Hello Hello India
There is a lot of demand these days
Internet Banking Online Banking which you
People talk more online these days.
The banking system was first started in India
ICICI Bank did it
Are you able to understand Sir ICICI Sher Holding
In ICICI Bank, the rate was reduced to 46 per
The public offer of shares in India follows
by equity or in the form of DR its
also American Depositary Receipt New Stock
The exchange took place in 2000 with III Bank
Add The Bank of Madura Limited in all stock
Deal in 2001 and Sold Additional Stake in
Institutional investors in 2001 in the
1990 ICICI Transforms its Business
From Development Financial Institution
of Auriol Project Finance to
Diversified financial services
How ICICI Bank is doing its business
I will tell you a little about the growth from here.
Idea is getting it later from ICICI.
Acquisitions were also made quite large.
Look at the actions the organization has taken.
A huge action was taken on this in Action 96.
Action means ICICI bought it.
Limited Diversified Financial
Institution with head quarters in
ITC Classic Finance Ltd. in India 97
This is an ITC company, isn't it? This is the full form of ITC.
Can anyone tell me the form
Have you heard the name of the company?
Have you heard of ITC please?
tell me yes sir can you tell me the full form
ITC
Does he have a hotel in Kolkata?
Is it an ITC hotel or not? It is very big.
Is it a five star hotel or is it not very big?
A seven-star type hotel is being built.
If you go next to Sin City, there's a
A huge hotel is being built there.
YTC's old front ever you say
If you go towards the city, there you will
Will be seen in Not Only in Kolkata, India
ITC has a company presence in many places.
Hotel Chan is a product of ITC.
Biscuits Your grocery store has lots of oil
Everything else is available in ITC's Indian
But its main business is cigarettes.
Cigarettes are Sir's business, that's what it is.
Most of it belongs to someone or some brand
I can definitely tell you the name of Aa's famous
The brand is Gold Flake, then what is yours?
The name is Papa uses
This is the Navy's Navy Card, all this is ITC's.
If the product is ok
ITC
Bolo ITC Classic Finance Ya
Incorporated later in 1986
I ha
Indian Tobacco Memo Yes Indian Tobacco
the company was called this is its name okay
A finance group was also formed which
Finance Imperial
Imperial Tea Company of India
Yes sir, okay, okay, sometimes I changed my name.
gaya hai itc ka full form indian or
If you had seen Imperial, I would have known
Tha Imperial S Imperial
What was the Indian name before?
Re Imperial Ya De Rename Ay Dekh Name Change
has been abolished by the Imperial Tobacco Company of
India Limited The Company or Rename Indian
Toko Company Limited in 1970 and late
ITC Limited In
Can you see 1974?
Yes, its first name was
It came under the name of Imperial Tobacco Company.
In the beginning, its name will be changed again.
Indian Tobacco Company was formed in 1970
Then now its name is just ITC Limited.
Only ITC Limited so if someone asks
what is the full form of ITC both are fine
Yes, but you should tell both the information.
Imperial Tobacco Company was established
It is fine in the name of and was changed later
Indian Tobacco Company means the latest change
There was but currently any of these two names
It is not used, it is an official name.
Its Indian Sorry ITC Limited Only
ITC Limited Its Geographic Scope
Mainly West Bengal is in India and it
Place of founding was right in Kolkata
and its base in food service is Sunrise's
Whatever happens, Sunrise Food Pvt.
Ltd. This is a very good company.
which is a brand under ITC
Okay, we are in the bank as well as in ITC.
Once gone because ITC Finance
Look sir, if you go to know one by one then
How does the second one come, business is like this sir
Doing one thing in business
There are many more options open before you.
It goes and you get the knowledge 197
In 1997, ICICI launched Shipping Credit
and Investment Corporation of India
Purchased shipping credit means that
shipbuilder
Government of India for their level
Sipping Credit and
Investment Corporation of India is
Acquired ICICI again
anagrammer or
Anagrammer had built up a network of 50
Branches in Gujarat, Rajasthan and
Maharashtra That's Primer Engages in Retail
Financing of Cars OK Car Financing
used to do specially trucks of specially trucks
Anna used to finance Ka Cars & Trucks
Gram Yena Gram has also been provided by ICICI
You can see Anna Gram as Anna Gram
Ko also got unified in 98 and see more sir
is not going to end In 2001, the Bank of
Madhura took it in 2002 in West Bengal
Darjeeling and Simla Branches of Greenley
Bank used to be called Bank, okay?
Greenleigh Bank used to be Bolke Bank
Darjeeling is the hill station of West Bengal
and the Shimla Home Station in Himachal Pradesh
You must have heard the names of both the places.
There used to be a bank in both these places.
It was a gridless bank, which was also taken over by ICICI.
taken
Investi Sino Credit Ini Bank Russian
The bank acquired it in 2005 in Sangli Sangli
Bank Vas Private Sector Unlisted Bank
Founded in 1916 and 30 on the Bathe
Family its head quarters in Sangli
Maharashtra, okay, this is a family matter.
It was the family bank, it was a local moneylender.
Maybe and it had a 198 branches 198
There are branches, I mean look sir, at the local level.
How much banking system is there in Maharashtra?
is and was it had 158 in Maharashtra and 31
In Karnataka, Maharashtra and Karnataka
I don't know this moneylender's business concept.
It is very old and was somewhere in Gujarat.
Andhra Pradesh, Tamil Nadu, Goa and Delhi
I also had these 150 and 198 in Sangli Bank
You can see which branch it was.
This was also at the organized level later.
ICICI Bank acquired
The Bank of Rajasthan was acquired by
ICICI Bank in 2010 for ₹ 30 billion
Dollar and RBI was critical of Bank of
Rajasthan Promoters Not Reduce There
Holdings in the company Good RBI Bank
The holder of Rajasthan is the promoter.
did not reduce his holding in the Bank of
Rajasthan has since been marching with the III
Bank since March with III Bank
If so, you can see how
what does iii bank mean to company
You have taken ownership, which means you can easily find out.
You can do this in details with people.
I will share it with you guys and see what happens.
Did you see this subsidiary company III
How many subsidiaries are under the bank?
If you look at the domestic level, I mean
Which is in India, that is ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance TV
You must have seen a lot, you must have seen
You might not have seen ICICI
Lord, this is also an insurance of this general
Insurance ICICI Lord Ye Upar Wala
There is Life and there is ICICI Lord.
No, he is a non-life person, meaning he is like a car.
Insurance Mobile Insurance
Accident Insurance Like Marine
Insurance Anything That Is Non-Life
ICICI Potential Asset Management
Company Asset Management means Sir, this mutual
The fund belongs to ICICI Prudential Trust
Ltd. is a trust owned by ICICI
National Pension Fund Management Company
ICICI Securities Stock Broking
The company is a stock broking company.
ICICI of stock broker ICICI
Security Primary Dealership Limited
ICICI Venture Fund Management Company
Limited means if you make a business then in that
These people manage ICICI
Investment Management Company Limited and
ICICI Trustee Trustee Services Ltd.
What do you get by knowing the names of so many companies?
Benefit: Yes, you get the second benefit of the exam.
The advantage is that you also get to know
Not that if there is so much organization then the area
How much space is there for the job area of ​​work?
Now we think that work is not work.
No sir, it's work, you just need to know.
Where do you want to reach, only government
We focus on getting a government job.
The area does not think about it at the government level.
I also have this like I am telling you this on private level
I am telling you in many levels.
Such work with government organizations
If we do, there are lots of things
Look at International, Sir ICICI Bank
Canada ICICI Bank USA III Bank
UK Plc III Bank Germany
ICICI Bank Eurasia Limited means
Europe and Asia combined
ICICI Security Holdings
ICICI Security International and
ICICI International Limited OK
ICICI's foreign approach is very
It's amazing, okay, there is foreign stuff here too.
A little bit of details have been given, you guys
must see bar okay so this was iii
Some things related to the bank that I told you
share
did if you saw ICICI ADFC
Let me bring you another thing as well.
Let me show you this ICICI currently.
What is HDFC's current infrastructure?
What is going on in the business level model?
Here's an idea to help you understand Indian
How is the banking system doing in India?
Which bank is good, which bank does what
okay you'll find out okay
Look sir, if the bank has a lot of money
If you have more capital then your money is also safe.
The second biggest thing is if you open an account
If you pay interest etc., you can get more.
The one who is good does the best he can.
Maybe the rest of the marketing is also something like
that you can see here I have
ADFC Bank is the top bank right now.
No, I join SBI later but
First you need to compare a little on a personal level.
I will get it done because at the government level
More to compare with SBI
There is no one, the loss is all here.
Mostly but you see in private level
You can check this out hdfcfund.com
It is visible to be seen
No, this is the current share price.
But I'm going to show you that
Peer Comparison of Current ADAC Bank
I will get you the market capital calculation.
Look at the market of ADFC Bank first
Capital Dekho Ya Dekho ADFC Kotak Mahindra
ICICI Access Bandhan India Current Affairs
I have listed the top private banks here.
ADFC Bank's market capitalization has been listed.
Capital
Look, count it please.
ADC has a market capital of Rs 6841 crore.
How much market share does Kotak Mahindra Bank have?
The capital is Rs 262 88.8 crore, how much of it
ICICI has one lakh rupees.
2540 is of access
3690 and is of Bandhan
The market capital is Rs 4937 crore.
This is how you get to know the current
At the top of the Indian banking system
Who is running market capital wise?
Meaning, who has the most business to do?
capital is available for ok good
Well, here you can see one thing.
I always tell you that the share price
Never compare more with less.
As you can see, the market for ADAC
Capital is high but ADAC Bank's share
The price is running at
Kotak of 104.5 right there
8 Paw 1328 ka Hello, are you getting the point?
Yes, if you guys understand what I'm saying then
Never think that such a mistake means common man
Not exactly like Because You Are the Commerce
Professionally, you should never make such a mistake.
To ensure that the one whose share is running high
Will the market capital be high or will its business
It's better that this doesn't happen, okay, that's it
You will learn everything while studying commerce.
Becoming Chartered CS Becoming CMA
While becoming you guys learn, okay share market
As you become a professional, you have to learn how to
It has no direct connection with the share price.
No connection, it's okay, whatever the price.
Can do market capital business with him
Scenario or money in your bank account
If this happens, you will get more interest.
There is no connection, okay you are here.
But you can see ADAC Bank Last 52
in a week means in the last one year
The share price reached its highest level of 1304
I'm okay there's Kotak Mahindra Bank
Highest share in last one year
Price has been in 1700 means 1739 1739
Correct
If it is there then take it at a low price and eat it as the last one
What was the lowest price of ADFC in the year?
Look at ICICI Bank's I think
No market capitalization second after ADFC
Kotak is in the third place in the second market.
ICICI Currents ICICI Business
The scenario has changed a bit now.
Due to some management problem due to some
Management
There is also a chapter on problem management.
I will also tell you that normally I am CMA
I make students do it and I am in class 12
I will also tell those who want to study management.
How the business is managed
go
is iii
Check the bank's share price
368 in the last one year, 552 were lost.
Went 269 Well look at one thing profit
Look at the profit, Bandhan Bank, you are watching
Currenty last price is 300 30650
The highest was 650 in the last 50 weeks
I went to 152, meaning you can see one thing.
Sir, look at the growth of Bandhan Bank from here.
You will know Bandhan Bank if you are a
Just one year back 152
If you had purchased in 2019, today your Bandhan Bank account will be
Look at the share price, it is 306, which means double.
Axis Bank's within a year
Even if you had purchased it a year ago for Rs 285
So your going today
445 ICICI Bank if you purchase for 269
So its growth is a bit competitive low but
Still not bad though
368 Look at this, if you buy it for Rs. 1000
hdfcfund.com AC's 5000 crore
Profit is being
Kotak, your profit is Rs 5000 crore.
There has been a profit of Rs 7000 crore
ICICI Axis has been profitable
1627 means 1627 crores but according to that
The market capital is quite low, just imagine
Check out the market capital of Bandhan Bank
Only 49000 compared to other big four
Two other big four but look at its profit 49
Its net profit in market capitalization of
yes sir
3237 crore means this tells you one thing.
I am wondering how the bond is growing.
How is Bandhan's growth going? View here
If you do more, you will see other banks also.
Dega ok HDFC Kotak ICICI
Axis Bandhan Indusind Yes You Small Finance
Some are IDFC First Bank Federal Bank
City Union RBL Ujjivan Small Finance
Karur Vaishnava DCB Karnataka South India
Bank Jammu Kashmir Lakshmi Vilas
Dhanalakshmi details of all these private banks
Yes, all these are private banks, okay I have
There is no government bank here.
Did you see anything and did you understand anything?
Did you come or did you enjoy seeing that currently
Reality at the Business Organization Level
what's up i just want to give a
I was doing a reality show for you guys.
Also, make sure that only what you are reading
What is the real fact going on with those people
Investing in the market and in the bank
People who are investing and looking at the market
Growing the business organization
Can you guys see how he's doing?
Yes, please tell me if you understand
I mean, if you are successful in mat, sir
If you look at the study mat, you will see
Obviously, know the details about the company
Okay, but I will tell you in real fact.
I told you to see what games are going on where.
So, that's how I told you that
I will also tell you that SBI is the government
Let's talk at a government level.
Let me talk about State Bank of
What is the situation in India?
Let us go
Situation of SB State Bank of India
Compare means Sir, it is worth thinking Sir, you are S.A.
Commerce professionals, many people will think and
You will think yourself and make others think too.
You will force me, okay, I have to force you.
Okay, compare it with State Bank also.
One should take one of the State Bank of Pierce
The share price is trading at 9.10 today.
The market is live now, it's okay, there's a little growth
It's okay, but first I'll tell you
I will tell you the details of State Bank later.
You mean the same with State Bank
to compare with other people who
It is at the government level, ok, this is State Bank
State Bank of India Case
If we look at the studies of State Bank of
India is a multinational company, its also foreign
These are government branches and public sector branches.
Bank Hai and Finance Service Statutory
The body is headquartered in Mumbai.
Maharashtra SBI ED 236 Fun Global 500
Dist of the World's Biggest Corporation of
2009 One of the World's Top 500 Companies
Is this a nationalized bank or a government bank?
It is the largest in India with 23 per
Market Share by Asset and 25 Share Total
Loan and Deposit Market in Total Market
If the total share of the business
Only SBI has 23 in banking assets.
I'm fine alone and
Loan and Deposit Market The Bank Descends
Where did the Bank of Kolkata come from?
Watch the story of SBI, SBI Descendants
Meaning this was the beginning of Bank of
Bank of India was formed before Kolka
Kolka Founded In
1806 The Bank of Calcutta was established in 1806 via the
I will tell you about Imperial Bank of India.
Normally I tell you Imperial Bank of
Made in India itself but its first
If there is any descendant, it is Bank Kalka.
with the Imperial Bank of India in 1806
Bhaiya Ho Ke Making The Oldest Commercial
Banks in the Indian Subcontinent Indian
Do you understand the meaning of subcontinent?
Do you know the meaning of subcontinent?
Indian subcontinent means any
Idea India could have said everything was contingent.
Why
said please tell
Are you guys listening and understanding or not?
or else
No, yes sir, what does subcontinent mean?
Tell me what does Indian subcontinent mean? India
Sane Jude Ba Awan
Not Nicobar, Baba, not like that, Indian
Subtinent means India, Total India
So it is fine, first of all tell me about the continent.
What does continent mean?
It happens that the continent is fine as we
Do you know how many continents there are in total?
Is
Australia, Asia, Africa
South America North
America Europe
Europe and here Antarctica too
hai ha antarctica neeche ni ekli to
Basically it is with all seven continents
By comparison, India is considered the largest city in the subcontinent.
I got dignity, that's why I got respect
Because India is so big, it has a
That's why India should have given respect
was considered a subcontinent
But within that subcontinent,
You are looking at Pakistan, look at this area.
Look at the area of ​​Pakistan, Pakistan, Nepal
and Bangladesh, Pakistan, India
Bangladesh, Nepal, Bhutan, all together
Together they are called Indian
subcontinent okay means this actually
In reality, India has a place all around.
Area which is old means very old time
This is totally India, that's why
Pakistan is just a few days away from us.
He forcibly quarreled and went here himself and
Bangladesh was created forcibly, yes only
It is okay to raise Hindu Muslim slogans.
Pakistani people means those from Pakistan
They are going to make it, it means it is very dangerous.
The one who created Pakistan, okay, means India.
I already mean the world in India
If the second largest Muslim lives then
There is no problem with Muslims.
Crores remain and what would have remained of 20 crores?
There is a problem but they had the thinking behind it.
had to show his different meaning and status and the world
I wanted to spread fear, so let's make it.
Yes, they wanted to make their own thing, so they made it.
Meaning force and Indian at that time who
There were people there, what do I mean, sir, be careful.
Subhash Chandra Bose would never have been there
I don't let history happen seriously.
I am not alone in saying this, whatever it is
The subcontinent that Pakistan snatched from us
This is actually a part of real India from here.
is made and another Bangladesh okay and
Nepal Bhutan or the complete area is called this
subcontinental y that I'm showing you
This complete subcontinent or subcontinent
The first bank in the
India which originated from the Bank of Calcutta
So you can understand that it was made by the British.
Making it the oldest commercial bank in
Indian Subcontinent The Bank of Madras
Merged into the other two Presidency Bank of
Madras other to presidency of banks in
There were other presidencies in British India like
Bank of Calcutta, Bank of Bombay
of Calcutta, Bank of Bombay and Bank of Madras
The three merge and form Imperial Bank
The three together formed the Imperial Bank.
Turned into the State Bank of India in 1955
After that in 1955 they were changed to State
Bank of India was formed by the Government of
India to control the Imperial Bank of
India in 1955 with Reserve Bank of India
Central Banks means Reserve Bank of
India has a stake, meaning a stake at that time.
The 60 per cent stake remaining in the State Bank of
India and named the Reserve Bank of India at 60
Took stake and gave it the name of State Bank
Meaning, basically you can assume that it is a state
Bank of India Reserve Bank of India
right, I mean, a bank, not a Ridge Bank business.
If Karta B does State Bank business then this
Like State Bank of India
Formation understood something State Bank of
of India
History ok formerly Imperial Bank of
India Dist Fm Bank Of Kolk Public Sector
NAC is listed in both BSC
I have told you the history, what next?
Let me tell you, let's look at some financial data.
Look here, it is very direct and found.
seconds
June 1806 Bank of Calcutta 15 April 1840
Bank of Bombay in July 1843
These three banks were formed in Madras
All three were marched to the
Imperial Bank of India was established.
State Bank of India was formed on 1 July 1955.
Off
India is a clear story
State Bank Bhawan MC Road Nariman Point
Its headquarter is in Mumbai, Area S
World Wide Hai Current Ki Peep Rajneesh Kumar
He is the chairman and his product is also same.
Like I told you about HDFC and ICICI
Explained in the case
Tha ok State Bank of India ka baaki
I'll take a look at the financial data.
Its current financial data is good with you
Let's do one thing: store its financial data
Let's see the rest of this with love, see this
State Bank of India had 187 shares in 6
Share Certificate of State Bank of India
This is how the Bank of Bengal used to look like
Issued by 13 out of 187 ok State Bank
There is also a stamp in the name of of India, meaning
The poster which is a postage stamp and this
The Imperial Bank logo would have looked like this
The logo of the Imperial Bank of India was like this
It used to look like the State Bank of
India's farmers are fine and this prosperity
Bhavan, if you ever visit this park in Kolkata
What is the name of that place on the banks of the Ganga? Who will tell you?
Who knows the name of Ganga Kinari Park?
Millennium Park Millennium Park Look
Everyone knows Millennium is not speaking.
If you ever go to a park, visit Millennium Park.
which is the second Millennium Park, there are 13 parks
There Millennium Park is located next to Second Park.
If you stand in front then you will get this
This is your Samriddhi Bhawan State Bank
of India's Eastern Zonal Office is ok
Meaning the Eastern State of entire Eastern India
This is the headquarter of Bank of India.
Is
Okay, okay, State Bank of India's name
There were a lot of associate banks, I mean
You can call it subsidiaries which are not currently
March is over, SBI awards the
Control of Seven Banks in 1960
This control was taken by the seven regional
Banks of Forman Indian Princely State
means different kings, different kings
The bank was of different princely states.
You will understand by looking at the state.
Renem meant the bank of those kings.
Prefix The State Bank of the Seven Banks
State Bank was added in front of his name
The State Bank of Bikaner and Jaipur
I understand this is the place of kings
Yours is in Rajasthan, okay Bikaner
Jaipur in Rajasthan
Look at this, you will see Jaipur.
Bikaner is visible, Bikaner Bikaner is very
It is on the western side, it is absolutely fine and some
Going far will take you to Pakistan.
It is the westernmost city of India.
The westernmost point, directly opposite the desert
Yes, Jaisalmer is fine, Bikaner is also like Jaisalmer.
It's nearby but a little far away
It is a little on the north side but is located in Jaisalmer
It's right in the desert, but here in Maine
It is about Jaipur and Bikaner, State Bank
Of Bikaner Jaipur, it belonged to the kings
Banks was there, okay, he took Banks.
taken
He took the bank and named it State Bank.
I went there and then there was State Bank of Indore State
Bank of Hyderabad State Bank of Mysore
State Bank Of Patiala Punjab in Patiala
Masor is in the South, okay in South India
Indore is the State Bank of Madhya Pradesh
Saurashtra, okay, this is a state in Gujarat.
Bank of Travancore, this is also good in South
All these are in Bankur South India.
Banks were given the same logo as the parent
Bank SBI State Bank of India and All
Its Associate Bank Use The Name Blue Key Hole
Like their logo is Blue's.
Whole OK, I said to be inspired by the
Ahmedabad Kankaria Lake in Ahmedabad
There is an article from Kankaria Lake.
Inspired by this, he became The State
Bank of India Word Mark Usually Had One
Standard Type Face Buttons Utilize Other
The type face is the World Bank's keyhole logo
Follow by SBI, okay, this word mark
that whole people you guys know the state
I am talking about these people of the bank.
I am this logo and not the hole
Are you able to understand or not?
You will start knowing about SBI.
So look, this state will never end.
Bank of India's South Hull United
Kingdom has branch in UK
I showed you the UK branch.
UK
Branch ok now I will compare you
Well, know a recent news.
Very recent about State Bank
Good State Bank of India Age Off in Other Services
March 3, 2017 The SBI Group Head
5991 ATMs since November 2017 SBI also
Offers Integrated Digital Banking
The platform is its name
oh okay integrated digital banking
Sir, when it became a share holding in the bank
So if Yes Bank suddenly collapses in the market
To save this
State Bank of India came but Reserve Bank
Bank of India has given its full commitment.
that we will never let you suffer a loss because
You also know about the Reserve Bank of India.
60% stake is already there in State Bank.
State Bank of India added 48.2% of the share
of S Bank as part of RBI directed
Rescue deal in March 2020 to SS Bank
I did not let it fall and that is the reason why
Sometimes any bank goes bad, right Indian?
The banking system does not collapse because
Reserve Bank of India will not let it fall.
gives ok good state bank of india
Who are the holders in this, see sir, who has it?
What is the shareholding of State Bank of
This is an interesting point in India.
The Government of India has the highest
at 56.2 at 5692 that's why there is a government bank
Foreign Institution Global Depository
NRI Bond Y Sab to 1094 Bank End
Insurance company's combined K 1063
Uni Trust of India Mutual Fund
1.72 Base Rate 7.79 Total 100%
This is how its shareholding is okay
How many employees does State Bank have?
There are many employees but here I am ME
Can't find data for Not found
9567 Most in banking sectors
ADC bank in seconds but quite far away
It is one lakh but still it is a private property.
They did a lot of harm but look at this government
They have 9567 employees, the rest are fine.
There is already a Scheduled Caste, Tribe quota, etc.
Okay, but what you had to understand was
I explained that
Let me show you a comparison, then go and
will be complete
Mains with Topic State Bank of India
The main government bank should be compared
IDBI Bank Punjab National Bank Union
Bank Bank of Baroda ok now State Bank
Look at the profit
14481 crores, this is the profit of State Bank
Check the market capitalization of State Bank of India
7689 is very high capital, even more than
HDFC, his was 5 lakhs, this one has 17 lakhs
Okay, but his profit was quite good.
Its worth Rs 26000 crore and yours worth Rs 14000 crore
You are understanding right, look at HDFC, ADFC
I showed you the profit of AC.
profit
Look, there was a profit of Rs 26000 crore.
The market capital of FC was Rs 96000.
And I am showing you the State Bank
The market capital is Rs 17,7689 crore.
But there is profit
1448 But it is a good bank, isn't it, it is a government bank.
Tswai Market also provides excellent service.
The stock was running high in the last one year
351 is currently running in low price, quite last 5
IDBI Bank was at its lowest level at 149 in the week.
Bank
12887 is in loss can you see it
ID bank ok very big in caper
IDBI Bank has 12800 branches.
There is a loss of Rs 12,000 crore in many places.
You can see the loss of Rs 12000 crore.
Sir, PNB's profit is Rs 336 crore.
The profit is fine, see the share price.
You can see the market capital
IDBI's market capitalization is estimated at Rs 31,525 crore.
The capital is
39342 crores, there is a loss of Rs 12000 in tax.
Union Bank of India has loss in 2008
Its market capital has a loss of Rs 2 crore.
Bank of Baroda has crores
Its market profit is 5461
Capital
2146 crores, then you will have to pay at the government level.
There is also an idea about the main banks.
I found someone else in the government job, sir, that too
See, slowly all the government work will end.
And the remaining four will remain SBI IDBI
PNB Union Bank Of Baroda I Have
Discus
Indian IOB Indian Overseas Bank is
What can I tell you, the situation is very bad.
Bank of India Canara Bank this is a little good
Work performed by Canara Bank UCO Bank
Central Bank Bank of Maharashtra Indian
Punjab and Sind Bank is one such bank.
If your government bank data is correct then
I told you about the government bank also.
I will give you a focus on State Bank.
If I compare it with others, I think that
You are connected with the Indian banking system.
The connection is done
will yes
Sir Hua
Hello Sir, did you understand what you thought
No, Kajal, Pragati, Vishwajeet understands.
came yes
Sir, the rest of you guys are just busy with your study mats.
Just spit it out once, I'll say it's fine.
Is Ina Kuga a B
Study
Bo
Karma
Tax
Ta Sher Recent
Lion Current
[music]
Ta
Oh, I understand that everyone enjoyed it so much.
Know about Sara Bank
K yes sir yes
Sir, it is very important
Do you guys bore me sometimes?
Yes sir, yes sir, it's okay, no problem
Okay, the result of Buy Account is about to come.
The result has been very bad in just a few days.
I will declare the copy thing is done sir
Sir, there are two or three more left.
I created a system that will
Created a pattern to check digitally
That's why it is taking some time, I mean your
I also have a copy of it all in digital format.
I am converting, by converting I
I am checking digitally, okay, no
So I will check how I mean later then I
You will have to write on a blank paper that there is a mistake here.
There's a mistake there, I was having a hard time
I have taken out digital and checked it in digital.
I discovered this yesterday, the day before yesterday.
If it is possible then I will also analyze it for you.
I will find where the mistake is going
Is
Ok ok then bye then bye sir bye sir bye